prettyopinionated.com 2019-06-08

# Privacy Policy - Pretty Opinionated

**Your Privacy**  
Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.

**  DoubleClick DART Cookie**  
Third party advertisement vendors use cookies to serve ads on this site. The use of DART cookies enables them to serve adverts to visitors that are based on their visits to this website as well as other sites on the internet.

To opt out of the DART cookies you may visit the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following url <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html> Tracking of users through the DART cookie mechanisms are subject to Google’s own privacy policies.

Other Third Party ad servers or ad networks may also use cookies to track users activities on this website to measure advertisement effectiveness and other reasons that will be provided in their own privacy policies, Pretty Opinionated has no access or control over these cookies that may be used by third party advertisers.

**Collection of Personal Information**  
When visiting @prettyopinionated the IP address used to access the site will be logged along with the dates and times of access. This information is purely used to analyze trends, administer the site, track users movement and gather broad demographic information for internal use. Most importantly, any recorded IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Links to third party Websites**  
We have included links on this site for your use and reference. We are not responsible for the privacy policies on these websites. You should be aware that the privacy policies of these sites may differ from our own.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

**Notice Regarding Online behavioral  Advertising**

We allow third party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our Web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g. click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice visit the NAI at http://www.networkadvertising.org. To  
opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit http://www.aboutads.info/choices.

Pretty Opinionated is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to  ([amazon.com](http://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2F&h=sAQH5jPSfAQFHyAYHoW3r7KOJ8KY14ZgInSYAwN85ptQM4w&enc=AZOOoh-7EALVpbu4z5f-du0eCN3Ejo393QyzrC75bzoyTm7smBU3N10itQ6AH-OjWOKZoVRT5ZmwIucdpdFq8DPHbcrQKmUWOSnOYyfoZch2Q8X6lP2HL2thbRjwrZjmjDwDHy36XRTbzDCwa0JQB4n7LEUHU22Sk7j1_K6wMaO8Lbf5Z34wFJuIjpHZ0uNJYMs&s=1)].” [https://affiliate-program.amazon.com/…/associates/agreement/](https://affiliate-program.amazon.com/gp/associates/agreement/)

**Changes to this Privacy Statement**  
The contents of this statement may be altered at any time, at our discretion.

If you have any questions regarding the privacy policy of @prettyopinionated.  you may contact us at prettyopinionated@gmail.com
